sesconference.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy - Search Engine Watch Search Engine Watch

This Privacy Policy describes the information that we gather on or through our Services and how we use and process such information. For each processing purpose we will articulate the reason for requiring the data, what data we will process, the legal basis for processing the data and how long we will keep the data.

Where the legal basis of consent is to be used, this will be gathered freely, and we will use clear, plain language that is easy to understand, and you will be able to remove your consent at any point.

**What information do we collect about you?**

We collect/process information so that we can provide the best possible experience when you utilise our services.  This section of the policy will describe the purpose for processing your personal data, the legal basis to do so and how long we will keep your data.

**Our Product / Service**

_If you choose to use our service, you must provide us with some personal data so that we can provide our services to you, this will include your name, email address, job title, company name, company type, company size, business type, company turnover and company region. Other non-mandatory personal data may also be gathered._

_We will process data using two legal rationales, if you are an individual and not associated with a contracted client we will ask for your consent. If you are associated with a contracted client we will use legitimate interest as the legal basis to process the data._

_Personal data will be retained for a period of up to 2 years for a dormant account, ie an account which hasn’t been used._

**Corporate**

_If you choose to use our service, personal data items such as Name, Email Address and Telephone number may be stored in our Corporate Cloud Storage, Corporate Email Platform or our Help Desk platform._

_We will process data using two legal rationales, if you are an individual and not associated with a contracted client we will ask for your consent. If you are associated with a contracted client we will use legitimate interest as the legal basis to process the data._

_Personal data will be retained for a period of up to 3 years for an active account, ie an account which has been used._

**Marketing**

_We would like to send you information about products and services of ours which may be of interest to you. You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes. The personal data will include names, addresses, email addresses, employer, job title and telephone numbers._

_We will process data using the following legal rationales to send marketing information, if you are an individual and not associated with a contracted client we will ask for your consent. If you are associated with a contracted client, we will use contractual obligation as the legal basis to process the data. If you are associated with a previous contracted client, we will use legitimate interest as the legal basis to process the data. All of the above rationales for marketing information can be removed by informing us of your wish to remove consent._

_We will retain personal data for active customer leads for a period of up to 1 year, a lead will be active under the following circumstances_

  * _An email sent by our organisation has not received an unknown account bounce back_
  * _An email has been sent to our organisation from the data subject_

**Cookies**

_Like many websites, we use cookies and similar technologies to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services. Website usage information is collected using cookies to monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed and web traffic routing on our Services. We will store the cookie values on our platform to allow us to perform our analysis, however this will not be used to target marketing material to an individual user._

_We will process data under the legitimate interest legal basis as we only use the data to perform aggregated tracking analysis and will not target individuals based upon this analysis and you also need to accept our cookie policy to allow us to process the data._

_We will retain active cookie data for a period of up to 1 year, a cookie will remain active if a user re-visits our platform._

Learn more about how we use cookies <https://www.searchenginewatch.com/cookie-policy/>

**Updating These Terms**

We may change our Service and policies, and we may need to make changes to these Terms so that they accurately reflect our Service and policies. Unless otherwise required by law, we will notify you at least 30 days before we make changes to these Terms and give you an opportunity to review them before they go into effect. Then, if you continue to use the Service, you will be bound by the updated Terms. If you do not want to agree to these or any updated Terms, you can request an account deletion.

**Your Rights**

Accessing or Rectifying your personal data

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date and you have the right to request a copy and update the personal data that we hold about you. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. If you would like to invoke this right, please email or write to us at the below address.

Deletion

Based upon the retention periods described above we will remove your personal data from our platforms.

Object, Restrict or Withdraw Consent

You may wish to object to or restrict our ability to process your personal data, this can be done either via email or in writing, using the contact details below. Further context may need to be requested to ensure we can carry out the relevant tasks on our platforms to perform the request.

Portability

You may wish to port your personal data to another platform. This can be done either via email or in writing, using the contact details below.

**Who we are and how to contact us**

We are the data controller responsible for defining and managing how your personal data is processed.

Our company name is Contentive Limited

Our company address is One Hammersmith Broadway, Hammersmith, London, W6 9DL

Our email address is [gdpr@contentive.com](mailto:gdpr@contentive.com)

**To Whom We Disclose Information**

Except as described in this Policy, we will not intentionally disclose the Personal Data or Client Data that we collect or store on the Service to third parties without the consent of the data subject. We may disclose information to third parties if you consent to us doing so, as well as in the following circumstances:

Unrestricted Information

Any information that you voluntarily choose to include in a Public Area of the Service, such as a public profile page, will be available to any Visitor or User who has access to that content.

Service Providers

We work with third party service providers who provide email hosting, core corporate applications, web hosting, maintenance, and other services for us. These third parties may have access to, or process Personal Data or Client Data as part of providing those services for us. We limit the information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their functions, and our contracts with them require them to maintain the confidentiality of such information.

Service providers include:

BC Foxtrot Limited, 1 Hammersmith Broadway, London W6 9DL; for the purpose of Hosting

Marketo EMEA, Limited, Cairn House, South Country Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland; for the purposes of Marketing and Email Campaigns

On24 Inc. Corporation Delaware, 201 Third Street, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94 103, USA; for the purposes of Webinar Marketing Campaigns

Mailchimp of The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA; for the purposes of Marketing and Email Campaigns

SurveyGizmo 4888 Pearl East Cir. Suite 100, Boulder, CO 80301 USA; for the purposes of Marketing Surveys

SurveyMonkey UK Limited, 6th Floor, One London Wall, London, EC2Y 5EB; for the purposes of Marketing Surveys

Overseas transfers

The information you provide may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) that do not have similar protections in place regarding your data and restrictions on its use as set out in this policy. However, we will take steps to ensure adequate protections are in place to ensure the security of your information. The EEA comprises the EU member states plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein. By submitting your information, you consent to these transfers for the purposes specified above.

We may transfer your personal information to the following which are located outside the European Economic Area (EEA) as follows:

Marketo EMEA, Limited, Cairn House, South Country Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland; for the purposes of Marketing and Email Campaigns

On24 Inc. Corporation Delaware, 201 Third Street, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94 103, USA; for the purposes of Webinar Marketing Campaigns

Mailchimp of The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA; for the purposes of Marketing and Email Campaigns

SurveyGizmo 4888 Pearl East Cir. Suite 100, Boulder, CO 80301 USA; for the purposes of Marketing Surveys

Marketo, On24, Mailchimp and SurveyGizmo have each provided the following safeguards to ensure the safety of your personal data, and it shall be processed to at least the same standards as set out by the General Data Protection Regulations: Marketo, On24, Mailchimp and SurveyGizmo each participates in The Privacy Shield framework, which is accepted by the European Commission as evidence that an adequate level of protection exists for the personal data in the country, territory, or organisation where it is being transferred, in this case, the United States.

You can obtain a copy of the safeguards and any other of Mailchimp’s data protection documentation by visiting https://mailchimp.com, or applying via post to Mailchimp, The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA.

You can obtain a copy of the safeguards and any other of Marketo data protection documentation by visiting https://www.marketo.com, or applying via post to Marketo EMEA, Limited, Cairn House, South Country Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland.

You can obtain a copy of the safeguards and any other of On24 data protection documentation by visiting https://www.on24.com, or applying via post to On24 Inc. Corporation Delaware, 201 Third Street, Suite 300, San Francisco, CA 94 103, USA.

You can obtain a copy of the safeguards and any other of SurveyGizmo data protection documentation by visiting https://www.surveygizmo.com, or applying via post to SurveyGizmo 4888 Pearl East Cir. Suite 100, Boulder, CO 80301 USA.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We may make non-personally-identifiable information available to third parties for various purposes. This data maybe automatically-collected and would be analysed to create an aggregated view of the data, ensure the reported information was anonymous.

Law Enforcement, Legal Process and Compliance

We may disclose Personal Data or other information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws, in response to a facially valid court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant, or to otherwise cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental agencies.

Change of Ownership

Information about data subject, may be disclosed and otherwise transferred to an acquirer, successor or assignee as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of assets, or similar transaction, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which information is transferred to one or more third parties as one of our business assets and only if the recipient of the personal data commits to a Privacy Policy that has terms substantially consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Our Data Security**

We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way.

The following security procedures, and technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal information have been put in place:

  * In cases where personal data is being processed in third countries or third parties, a rigorous data protection impact assessment is being performed to ensure that your data is always secured.
  * Our application platform is hosted in ISO 27001 certified secure data centres in the UK.
  * Firewalls, intrusion detection and prevention, anti-virus and anti-malware and backup and disaster recovery is in place to prevent data loss or deletion.
  * 24/7 security guard, closed circuit television and a door access control system to authorized personnel secures our offices and data centres.
  * Our applications are engineered by following industry standards to minimise security vulnerabilities and updates on a regular basis.
  * Intrusion detection and prevention secures the network traffic to the servers and applications.
  * Anti-malware and anti-virus software is deployed to all of our servers and regularly scan and update with the latest anti-malware and virus signatures.
  * We regularly apply critical, security patches and firmware updates to operating systems and physical hardware to minimise the risk of vulnerabilities
  * Our employees undergo background screening and selection processes, with a restricted list of employees having access to secure areas of the applications, databases and physical infrastructure. The access to the secure areas are logged and auditable.
  * We will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal information. However, you should be aware that the use of the Internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal information which is transferred from you or to you via the Internet.
  * We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
  * We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

This privacy policy was last updated on 23 May 2018.
